HARRY COLLINS

SUMMARY

With three years of experience in the energy industry working across various parts of the value chain, I have developed a keen interest in finance and trading. Currently I am actively managing my own money in equities, FX, options, bonds and ETFs using a long/short global macro approach.

EDUCATION

Studying for CFA level 1 (Nov 2022)

University of Warwick

Postgraduate Diploma in Mathematics

October 2018

University of Brighton

BSc (Hons) in Mathematics and Finance – 1st class

June 2016

Awarded The DEB Bose Prize for the Best Project from a Mathematical Sciences degree

IT Skills: VBA (advanced), SAS (intermediate), Python (beginner)

Languages: Japanese (semi-conversational)

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

National Grid Interconnectors

January 2019 - Present

Roles include Energy trader and Quantitative analyst

- Power trading across French and Belgian Interconnectors, 24/7 desk covered by a team of five
- Developed implemented and documented trading and risk management tools, for trading across French and Belgian interconnectors
- Analysis on the NSL Interconnector
- Ad hoc trading analysis

ELEXON

June 2018 - January 2019

Market Analyst

- Analysis and implementation of changing the CADL pricing parameter from 15 to 10 minutes
- P350 "Introduction of a seasonal Zonal Transmission Losses scheme" analysis
- ISG Technical Secretary
- Delivered training on imbalance pricing at the ELEXON seminar

Institute of Trading and Portfolio Management "Professional Trading Masterclass"

November 2013 - December 2013

- Statistical Distribution of Asset Returns, OHLC Volatility calculation, Implied Volatility Assessment across Equities, Currencies, Commodities and Rates.
- Top Down Macroeconomic Asset Selection Process Trade Idea Generation across Indices, Commodities, Currencies and Rates.
- Top Down and Bottom Up appraisal for Sector and Stock selection. GDP Correlation (Lag Effects) to Asset Prices, Industry Sector (Value Chain) analysis, Stock analysis (Fundamental, Technical, Price Action) – Trade Idea Generation for Alpha.
- Risk Management Watchlist generation (Technical and Price Action overlay), Trade Selection, Beta Hedging (Equities), Portfolio Construction Parameters, Kelly Criterion (All Asset Classes).

Examination Mark: 94% (Distinction).